Emanuel Ruben Piore Papers ca.1918-1986 Mss.Ms.Coll.80
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Subject files, 1930-1986; 32 boxes; 16 linear feet (Box Series I: 1-32)
  - Revelle, Roger, 1909-, 1984; 4 items
  - Rice, Donald B., 1977; 2 items
  - Rice, Stuart Alan, 1932- -- TMs Cy, n.d.; 1 item
  - Rich, Alexander -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1976 September 28; 1 item
  - Richards, Hugh T. (Hugh Taylor), 1918-, 1978; 2 items
  - Richardson, E. P., 1978; 2 items
  - Rimon, Pinhas, 1973; 3 items
  - Ripley, Sidney Dillon, 1913-, 1984; 2 items
  - Ritz-Carlton Hotel Co., 1980-1981; 2 items
  - Roberts, John D., 1918-, 1977-1982; 4 items
  - Robinson, James D., 1977; 2 items
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1910-, 1973-1979; 5 items
  - Rockefeller University, 1968-1985; 15 folders
    - Folder 1, 1968; 3 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 10 items
    - Folder 3, 1971March-May; 10 items
    - Folder 4, 1971 June-July; 8 items
    - Folder 5, 1971 August; 10 items
    - Folder 6, 1971 September-October; 20 items
    - Folder 7, 1971 November-December; 20 items
    - Folder 8, 1972 January-March; 15 items
    - Folder 9, 1972 April; 15 items
    - Folder 10, 1972 May; 12 items
    - Folder 11, 1972; 4 items
    - Folder 12, 1973-1975; 21 items
    - Folder 13, 1976; 16 items
    - Folder 14, 1978-1980; 30 items
    - Folder 15, 1981-1985; 21 items
  - Romanoff, Gloria -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 August 9; 1 item
  - Roosevelt Hospital (New York, N.Y.), 1977-1978; 7 items
  - Rose, Albert, 1910-, 1975; 3 items
  - Rose, David, 1973-1978; 7 items
  - Rose, Frederick -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1984 August 21; 1 item
  - Rosen, Richard M., 1972; 8 items
  - Rosenblith, Walter A. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1976 May 3; 1 item
  - Ross, Ian M. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 May 4; 1 item
  - Rostow, W. W. (Walt Whitman), 1916- -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 May 5; 1 item
  - Roy, Robert H. -- TLS from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1976 February 3; 1 item
  - Royal Society (Great Britain), 1939, 1976-1979; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1939; 1 item
    - Folder 2, 1976-1979; 16 items
  - Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain), 1969-1978; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1969; 17 items
    - Folder 2, 1970-1978; 12 items
  - Rozett, John Michael, 1979; 2 items
  - Ruben, Samuel -- TLS, 1981 April 22; 1 item
  - Rubey, William Walden, 1898-1974., 3 items
  - Russotto, Leo, 1975; 5 items
    Included photograph of Piore as a boy. Removed to Series V.
  - Saarinen, Eero, 1910-1961., 2 items
  - Sachs, Joel -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, n.d.; 1 item
  - Sadnytzky, Nicholas O., 1972-1973; 6 items
  - Sakharov, Andrei, 1921-, 1984; 4 items
  - Salkin, Nancy -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1979 August 15; 1 item
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1971-1981; 5 items
  - Sapovits, Adeline, 1971; 2 items
  - Sarett, Lewis Hastings, 1917-, 1980; 2 items
  - Savin, Robert -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 May 5; 1 item
  - Schenk, K, 1981; 2 items
  - Scher, Charles I., 1976; 2 items
  - Schmidt, Benno C., 1942-, 1976-1985; 9 items
  - Schmitt, Roland W., 1982-1984; 6 items
  - Schorr, Daniel, 1916- -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 April 10; 1 item
  - Schwartz, Bernard, 1923-, 1976; 7 items
  - Science., 1975-1984; 6 items
  - Science Associates, 1968-1970; 7 items
  - Science Center, 1981; 3 items
  - Science museums, 1976-1978; 12 items
  - Science Research Associates., 1978-1981; 4 items
  - Science Research Associates. -- Board of Directors, 1964-1970; 25 items
  - Scientific Research Society of America, 1951-1970; 10 items
  - Science and Technology Advisory Council, 1974 January 30; 1 item
  - Scientific American -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 April 12; 1 item
  - Scientific Energy Systems Corporation -- TLS to Piore, Emanual Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 May 6; 1 item
  - Scientists Institute for Public Information, 1975-1981; 6 items
  - Scott, John -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 March 1; 1 item
  - Scranton, William Warren, 1917-, 1975-1980; 8 items
  - Screvane, Paul R., 1978; 2 items
  - Scripps Clinic and Research Foundation, 1980; 2 items
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1911-, 1977-1978; 3 items
  - Selby, Cecily Cannan, 1981-1985; 3 items
  - Senko, Michael E., 1974; 3 items
  - Serber, R. (Robert), n.d.; 1 item
  - Sevcenko, Ihor, 1986; 2 items
  - Seymour, Francis X., 1972; 2 items
  - Seymour, William -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 May 9; 1 item
  - Shannon, Claude Elwood, 1916-, 1977-1983; 3 items
  - Shannon, James A., 1904-, 1980; 3 items
  - Shaw, Paula -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 January 19; 1 item
  - Sheldon, Eleanor B. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 February 3; 1 item
  - Sherman Fairchild Foundation, 1980; 2 items
  - Shilling, Charles W. (Charles Wesley), 1977; 3 items
  - Shillito, Barry J. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1973 January 31; 1 item
  - Shinder, Seymour, 1979-1985; 4 items
  - Shiung, Chien -- TLS Cy to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 May 3; 1 item
  - Shull, Harrison, 1979-1983; 5 items
  - Sidwell Friends School (Washington, D.C.) -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 February 23; 1 item
  - Siffert, Robert S. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1986 October 7; 1 item
  - Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society of North America., 1980-1983; 2 items
  - Silverman, Elizabeth, 1980; 2 items
  - Silverman, Selig J. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 November 19; 1 item
  - Simo, Constance, 1939-, 1979-1980; 5 items
  - Sinsheimer, Robert Louis, 1973-1978; 3 items
  - Skinner, Priscilla -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 Febraury 13; 2 items
  - Slichter, Charles P. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 April 6; 1 item
  - Sloan Commission on Cable Communications, 1970-1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1970; 10 items
    - Folder 2, 1971; 19 items
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research -- Search Committee, 1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971 January-March; 25 items
    - Folder 2, 1971 April- December; 21 items
  - Smith, Dereka, 1974; 3 items
  - Social Science Research Council (U.S.) -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 September 15; 1 item
  - Social Security Notice, 1982 December 11; 1 item
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1970; 7 items
  - Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 1973-1984; 5 folders
    - Folder 1, 1973-1974; 9 items
    - Folder 2, 1975; 15 items
    - Folder 3, 1977 February-April; 8 items
    - Folder 4, 1977 June-August; 11 items
    - Folder 5, 1978-1984; 20 items
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1918-, 1975; 2 items
  - Soutter, Lamar, 1976; 2 items
  - Spaulding, Donald T., 1982; 3 items
  - Speiser, Ambros P., 1922-, 1974-1984; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1974-1979; 18 items
    - Folder 2, 1980; 13 items
    - Folder 3, 1983-1985; 4 items
  - Sponsler, George, 1976; 3 items
  - Sporn, Philip, 1896-1978, 2 items
  - Sprague, Robert C., 1975-1985; 3 items
  - Stanford University, 1982; 7 items
  - Starr, Chauncey, 1979; 4 items
  - State University of New York, 1972-1982; 10 items
    Includes photograph of the First U.S Math Olympiad 1972 opening ceremony. James Bergheim Saxe, Emanuel Ruben Piore, and Samuel L. Greitzer. Removed to Series V.
  - Stern, Robert L., 1977; 2 items
  - Stetten, DeWitt, 1909-, 1977; 2 items
  - Stever, H. Guyford, 1975; 2 items
  - Steward, Patricia C. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 November 19; 1 item
  - Stibitz, George R. (George Robert), 1904- -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 September 19; 1 item
  - Stolberg, David F., 1975 May 1; 2 items
  - Stone, Marshall H. (Marshall Harvey), 1903- -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 March 30; 1 item
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1977; 2 items
  - Suppes, Patrick, 1922- -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 April 29; 1978
  - Surface Activation Corporation, 1978-1980; 3 items
  - Susskind, Charles -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977; 2 items
  - Sviridoff, Michael, 1979; 2 items
  - Swartz, William M., 1975-1983; 17 items
  - Swope, Gerard, 1906-1979, 3 items
  - Szakonyi, Robert -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 September 15; 1 item
  - S miscellaneous, 1975-1985; 7 items
  - Taft, Philip, 1902-, 1976; 1 item
  - Technology in society, 1979-1980; 3 items
  - Tekhniyon, Makhon tekhnologi le-Yisra'el., 1973-1974; 9 folders
    - Folder 1, 1973-1974; 21 items
    - Folder 2, 1975; 36 items
    - Folder 3, 1976 January-March; 8 items
    - Folder 4, 1976 May-November; 20 items
    - Folder 5, 1977; 33 items
    - Folder 6, 1978-1979; 13 items
    - Folder 7, 1980; 16 items
    - Folder 8, 1981-1982; 20 items
    - Folder 9, 1983-1985; 10 items
      Included group photograph at the reception and Open house in honor of Carl Alpert, 25 January 1983. Removed to Series V.
  - Tekhniyon, Makhon tekhnologi le-Yisra'el. -- Science Advisory Committee Meeting, 1975 June 27; 15 items
  - Terenzio, Joseph V., 1986; 2 items
  - Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-, 1975-1977; 5 items
  - Terman, Lewis M., 1975 February 13; 1 item
  - Texaco, inc., 1978; 1 item
  - Thomas, Franklin A., 1979; 2 items
  - Thomas, Lewis, 1913-, 1982-1983; 2 items
  - Thomsen, Donald L., 1921-, 1984; 10 items
  - Ting, S. C. C. (Samuel Chao-chung) 1936-, 1976-1977; 3 items
  - Tobin, James, 1918-, 1981; 2 items
  - Tomash, Erwin, 1979; 2 items
  - Tordella, Louis W. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 February 21; 1 item
  - Travelers Insurance Company, 1982; 2 items
  - Tucker, Gardiner L., 1925-, 1971; 2 items
  - Tulane University -- Board of Visitors, 1965-1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1969; 11 items
    - Folder 2, 1971; 24 items
  - Turner, Nura D., 1972-1984; 3 items
  - Tuve, Merle Antony, 1901-1982., 1981-1983; 4 items
  - Ueda, Tomonori, 1973; 2 items
  - Uhlenbeck, George Eugene, 1900- -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 November 28; 1 item
  - Ulam, Stanislaw M. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1984 May 16; 1 item
  - Ullmann, Jacob W., 1985; 2 items
  - Union of Concerned Scientists -- TLS, 1985 March 12; 1 item
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1982; 4 items
  - Union University (Schenectady, N.Y.), 1962; 6 items
  - United Hospital Fund of New York., 1979-1980; 7 items
  - United Jewish Appeal--Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New, 1974-1983; 10 items
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 1973; 7 items
  - United States Civil Service Commission., 1962-1970; 23 items
  - United States. Committee on Science and Technology, 1972-1984; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1972-1973; 3 items
    - Folder 2, 1975; 3 items
    - Folder 3, 1976-1978; 10 items
    - Folder 4, 1980-1984; 6 items
  - United States. Congress, 1965-1975; 21 items
  - United States. Dept. of Commerce., 1965-1985; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1972; 19 items
    - Folder 2, 1975-1985; 20 items
  - United States. Dept. of Defense., 1955-1975; 5 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955; 16 items
    - Folder 2, 1956-1957; 18 items
    - Folder 3, 1961; 15 items
    - Folder 4, 1962-1964; 12 items
    - Folder 5, 1965-1975; 18 items
  - United States. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1955-1979; 27 items
  - United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 February 25; 1 item
  - United States. Dept. of State., 1965-1970; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1966; 7 items
    - Folder 2, 1967-1970; 14 items
  - United States. Energy Research and Development Adminstration, 1975; 3 items
  - United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1963-1971; 24 items
  - United States. National Bureau of Standards, 1964-1972; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1964-1967; 35 items
    - Folder 2, 1968-1972; 20 items
  - United States. National Security Agency., 1971-1972; 24 items
  - United States. Navy Dept., 1955-1969; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1963; 27 items
    - Folder 2, 1964-1966; 17 items
    - Folder 3, 1968-1969; 16 items
  - United States. Office of Naval Research, 1948-1976; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1948-1958; 20 items
    - Folder 2, 1964-1966; 31 items
    - Folder 3, 1967-1977; 21 items
  - United States. Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology, 1979; 2 items
  - Universitah ha-Ivrit bi-Yerushalayim., 1970-1986; 9 folders
    - Folder 1, 1970; 8 items
    - Folder 2, 1972 March-April; 14 items
    - Folder 3, 1972 May-Dec; 11 items
    - Folder 4, 1974-1975; 12 items
    - Folder 5, 1976-1977; 29 items
      Includes four group photographs at the Kaplun Awards. Removed to Series V.
    - Folder 6, 1978-1979; 9 items
    - Folder 7, 1980-1981; 27 items
      Includes four photographs of the Society of Research Founders of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem.
    - Folder 8, 1982-1983; 31 items
    - Folder 9, 1984-1986; 23 items
  - Universitat Bar-Ilan, 1985 August 15; 1 item
  - University Club of New York, 1971-1981; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971-1976; 33 items
    - Folder 2, 1977-1981; 16 items
  - University of Colorado, Boulder., 1979; 3 items
  - University of Colorado, Boulder. -- George Gamow Memorial Prize, 1971; 6 items
  - University of the District of Columbia, 1982; 4 items
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign., 1983; 3 items
  - University of New Hampshire -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 September 30; 1 items
  - University of Rochester, 1973, 1983; 2 item
  - University Seminar on Technology and Social Change, 1975; 3 items
  - University of Tennessee (System). Space Institute -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1974 April 26; 1 item
  - University of Wisconsin, 1955-1985; 10 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1959; 11 items
    - Folder 2, 1961; 22 items
    - Folder 3, 1963-1964; 8 items
    - Folder 4, 1966 March-July; 27 items
    - Folder 5, 1966; 12 items
    - Folder 6, 1968-1974; 20 items
    - Folder 7, 1976-1979; 10 items
    - Folder 8, 1980 February-June; 19 items
    - Folder 9, 1980 July-December; 14 items
    - Folder 10, 1982-1985; 20 items
  - University of Wyoming, 1978-1984; 18 items
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1955-1970; 5 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1961; 24 items
    - Folder 2, 1962-1964; 14 items
    - Folder 3, 1965; 13 items
    - Folder 4, 1966; 19 items
    - Folder 5, 1965-1970; 24 items
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission -- High Energy Physics Advisory Panal, 1970-1971; 15 items
  - Vance, Cyrus R. (Cyrus Roberts), 1917-, 1976; 2 items
  - Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-, 1971-1976; 6 items
  - Vargas, Carlos Armando, 1981-1982; 3 items
  - Varian Associates -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1976 April 23; 1 item
  - Varner, John, 1981; 6 items
  - Veeco Instruments, inc. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 December 16; 1 item
  - Vilno in Pictures, inc. -- TL Cy From Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 March 17; 1 item
  - Wahlin, Hugo Bernard, 1894-1971, 3 items
  - Walkowicz, T. F., 1978-1983; 8 items
  - Wang, -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1981 May 18; 1 item
  - Warburg, Edward M.M., 1968-1971; 21 items
  - Warner, Aaron W., 1908-, 1978; 3 items
  - Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.), 1952; 2 items
  - Washington Technical Institute -- Board of Vocational Education, 1967; 12 items
  - Watergate Hotel -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1979 July 10; 1 item
  - Watson, Richard, 1974; 7 item
  - Weaver, Warren, 1894-1978, 1978-1984; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1978; 11 items
    - Folder 2, 1979-1984; 9 items
  - Wechler, Jacqueline -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 August 17; 1 item
  - Wechsler, Harry C., 1979; 2 items
  - Weinberg, Alvin Martin 1915-, 1979; 3 items
  - Weinberg, Stanley L., 1986; 6 items
  - Weinschel, Bruno O., 1979; 3 items
  - Wellington, Enid -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 January 19; 1 item
  - Wessell, Nils Y., 1975; 4 items
  - Western Union International, inc., 1980; 2 items
  - Westinghouse Educational Foundation, 1979; 1 item
  - Wexler, Jacqueline G. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 September 1; 1 item
  - Wheaton, Bruce R., 1978; 2 items
  - Wheeler Laboratories -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 February 26; 1 item
  - White, Robert M., 1938- -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 March 25; 1 item
  - Whitmore, Willet F., 1983; 2 items
  - Who's who in America., 1976-1977; 12 items
  - Who's who in frontiers of science and technology., 1985; 7 items
  - Who's who in technology today. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1986 January 6; 1 item
  - Who's who in world Jewry., 1980-1985; 2 items
  - Wiesner, Jerome B., 1977-1980; 7 items
  - Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902- -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1972 May 16; 1 item
  - Williams Club, 1970 March 26; 1 item
  - Williams, Albert L., 1982-1983; 4 items
  - Wilson, Kenneth, 1926- -- TL Cy from Pioer, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1984 May 12; 1 item
  - Winograd, Shmuel, 1978; 2 items
  - Wishina, Yulchiro -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 January 14; 1 item
  - Wittmore, Willet -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 January 7; 1 item
  - Wohlman, Alan -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 December 13; 1 item
  - Wolf, Mary Hunter, 1984; 2 items
  - Woollcombe, David, 1983; 2 items
  - Woolf, Harry, 1977-1978; 8 items
  - World ORT Union, 1984-1986; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1984; 18 items
    - Folder 2, 1985; 16 items
      Includes group photograph of ORT at Oxford, October 1984
    - Folder 3, 1986; 10 items
  - Wu, C. S. (Chien-shiung) 1912-, 1977; 5 items
  - Yale University -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1974 December 30; 1 item
  - Yamazaki, A. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 October 31; 1 item
  - Yangarber, Victor, 1976; 7 items
  - Yokoyama, Sumi, 1983 November 7; 1 item
  - Zacharias, Jerrold Reinach, 1905-1986., 1975-1983; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1975-1977; 9 items
    - Folder 2, 1983; 3 items
  - Zahl, Harold -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1973 March 13; 1 item
  - Zare, Richard N. -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1985 June 10; 1 item
  - Zeta Beta Tau Foundation, inc., 1980-1985; 7 items
  - Zinn, Walter H. (Walter Henry), 1906-, 1974; 2 items
  - Zucker, Paul A., 1974; 3 items
- Series II. IBM, 1956-1986; 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet (Box Series II: 1-3)
  Correspondence and subject files relating only to Piore's concluding years at IBM as a vice president, Chief Scientist, and as a member of the board in addition to his years as an unofficial IBM consultant after he retired.
  - General files, 1965-1986; 52 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1969; 30 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 8 items
    - Folder 3, 1971 February-July; 18 items
    - Folder 4, 1971 November; 13 items
    - Folder 5, 1971 December; 13 items
    - Folder 6, 1972 January; 13 items
    - Folder 7, 1972 February; 27 items
    - Folder 8, 1972 March; 17 items
    - Folder 9, 1972 April-June; 25 items
    - Folder 10, 1972 July-August; 19 items
    - Folder 11, 1972 September-October; 15 items
    - Folder 12, 1972 November-December; 13 items
    - Folder 13, 1973 January-April; 23 items
    - Folder 14, 1973 May #1; 4 items
    - Folder 15, 1973 May #2; 1 item
    - Folder 16, 1973 June-December; 8 items
    - Folder 17, 1974 March-April; 11 items
      Includes photograph of Dr. David Sayre. Removed to Series V.
    - Folder 18, 1974 June-July; 4 items
    - Folder 19, 1974 October-November; 8 items
    - Folder 20, 1974 December; 4 items
    - Folder 21, 1975 January-February; 14 items
    - Folder 22, 1975 April-May; 5 items
    - Folder 23, 1975 July-December; 11 items
    - Folder 24, 1976 January-March; 19 items
    - Folder 25, 1976 May #1; 1 item
    - Folder 26, May 1976 #2; 5 items
    - Folder 27, 1976 June-September; 9 items
    - Folder 28, 1976 October-November; 13 items
    - Folder 29, 1977 February-August; 13 items
    - Folder 30, 1977 September-December; 21 items
    - Folder 31, 1978 February-June; 10 items
    - Folder 32, 1978 July; 7 items
    - Folder 33, 1978 July; 2 items
    - Folder 34, 1978 August-December; 16 items
    - Folder 35, 1979 January-February; 9 items
    - Folder 36, 1979 April; 5 items
    - Folder 37, 1979 May-December; 6 items
    - Folder 38, 1980; 15 items
    - Folder 39, 1981 January-February; 22 items
    - Folder 40, 1981 April-July; 8 items
    - Folder 41, 1981 September-October; 11 items
    - Folder 42, 1981 November-December; 16 items
    - Folder 43, 1982 January; 11 items
    - Folder 44, 1982 February; 6 items
    - Folder 45, 1982 June-December; 20 items
    - Folder 46, 1983 January-September; 21 items
    - Folder 47, 1983 October-December; 10 items
    - Folder 48, 1984 January-March; 16 items
    - Folder 49, 1984 April-July; 23 items
    - Folder 50, 1984 September-December; 28 items
    - Folder 51, 1985; 32 items
    - Folder 52, 1986; 6 items
  - Board of Directors, 1971-1973; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971 January-July; 14 items
      Included group photograph of most likely Board of Directors. Removed to Series V.
    - Folder 2, 1971 August -1973; 23 items
  - Contracts, 1973-1974; 9 items
  - Japan, 1981-1983; 16 items
  - Personal, 1956-1970; 29 items
  - Science Advisory Committee, 1971-1981; 10 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971; 1 item
    - Folder 2, 1972 January-April; 6 items
    - Folder 3, 1972 May-October; 10 items
    - Folder 4, 1973 January-June; 4 items
    - Folder 5, 1973 July-December; 12 items
    - Folder 6, 1974-1975; 7 items
    - Folder 7, 1976; 6 items
    - Folder 8, 1977-1979; 8 items
    - Folder 9, 1980; 7 items
    - Folder 10, 1981; 17 items
  - Travel, 1966-1969; 6 folders
    - Folder 1, 1958-1964; 40 items
    - Folder 2, 1966; 40 items
    - Folder 3, 1967; 40 items
    - Folder 4, 1968; 40 items
    - Folder 5, 1969; 40 items
    - Folder 6, 1970-1971; 30 items
- Series III. Speeches, 1951-1982; 5 boxes; 2.5 linear feet (Box Series III: 1-5)
  An important series of Piore's speeches highlighting his dedication to federal funding of scientific and industrial research at the univeristy level.
  - [Untitled], 1951 May 18; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Mobilazation of Science, 1951 December 14; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Prepared for House Budget Hearings, 1951 May 22; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Address before the USN PG School, 1952; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Physical Society Dinner, 1952 May 2; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Round Table Conference on "Basic Research", 1952 September 10; 12 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Aims of Industry, the Universities and Gevernment in Their Conduct and Support of Research (the Need for Research)", 1953 August 31; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - [Department of Defence Development Program], 1953 March 11; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Talk Before the West Coast Naval Research Reserves, 1953 August 17; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - [Navy], 1954 May 27; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Office of Naval Research Policy, 1954 May; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Some Thougths on Federal Science, 1954 April 30; 4 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Underwater Sound Advisory Committee, 1954 September 14; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Research and the Future, 1955 April 23; 9 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Engineering Creativity, 1956 April 18; 10 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000